She isn't coming yet, Toto.
Did she hurt you?
She tried to, didn't she?
Come on. We'll go tell
Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
Aunt Em!
Listen to what Miss Gulch
did to Toto--
Dorothy, please!
We're counting!
-But she hit him--
-Don't bother us now, honey.
The incubator's gone bad and we're
likely to lose a lot of our chicks.
That poor little thing.
But Miss Gulch hit Toto with a rake...
...because she says he chases
her nasty old cat every day!
--seventy.
Dorothy, please!
But he doesn't do it every day!
Just once or twice a week.
And he can't catch her old cat anyway.
Now she says she'll--
Dorothy! We're busy.
Oh, all right.
-How's she coming?
-Take it easy.
You got my finger!
Why don't you get your finger
out of the way?
-There you are.
-Right on my finger!
Lucky it wasn't your head!
Zeke, what am l going to do about
Miss Gulch? Just because Toto--
Listen, honey,
l got them hogs to get in.
You ain't using your head.
You'd think you didn't have any brains.
l have so got brains!
Why don't you use them?
Don't go by Miss Gulch's place.
Then Toto won't get in her garden,
and you won't get in no trouble.
Oh, Hunk, you just
won't listen, that's all.
Well, your head ain't made
of straw, you know.
Get in there before l make
a dime bank out of you!
Listen, kid...
...are you gonna let that old Gulch
heifer try and buffalo you?
She ain't nothing to be afraid of.
Have a little courage.
l'm not afraid of her.
Next time she squawks,
walk up to her and spit in her eye.
That's what l'd do.
Help me, Zeke!
Get me out of here!
Help!
-Are you all right, Dorothy?
-Yes, l'm all right.
l fell in and Zeke--
Why, Zeke, you're just
as scared as l am!
You gonna let a little pig
make a coward out of you?
Look at you--
What's all this jabber-wapping
when there's work to be done?
l know three farm hands
that'll be out of a job!
Dorothy was--
l saw you tinkering with
that contraption, Hickory.
-You and Hunk get back to that wagon.
-All right.
But someday they'll erect
a statue to me--
Well, don't start posing for it now.
Can't work on an empty stomach.
Have some crullers.
-Gosh, Mrs. Gale.
-Just fried.
You see, Dorothy toppled into the--
lt's no place for Dorothy
around a pigsty!
Feed those hogs before they
worry themselves into anemia!
Do you know what Miss Gulch
said she was going to do to Toto?
-She said she'd--
-Stop imagining things.
You're always in a fret over nothing.
You just help us out today...
...and find a place where
you won't get into any trouble.
Someplace where there
isn't any trouble.
Do you suppose there is
such a place, Toto?
There must be.
lt's not a place you can get to
by a boat or a train.
lt's far, far away.
Behind the moon...
...beyond the rain....
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
Way up high
There's a land that I heard of
Once in a lullaby
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
Skies are blue
And the dreams that you dare to dream
Really do come true
Someday I'll wish upon a star
And wake up where the clouds
are far behind me
Where troubles melt like lemon drops
Away above the chimney tops
That's where you'll...
...find me
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
Bluebirds fly
Birds fly Over the Rainbow
Why then...
...oh, why can't I?
If happy little bluebirds fly
Beyond the rainbow
Why, oh, why...
...can't I?
Mr. Gale.
Howdy, Miss Gulch.
l want to see you and
your wife about Dorothy.
-What has Dorothy done?
-What's she done?
l'm all but lame from
the bite on my leg!
-You mean, she bit you?
-No, her dog!
She bit her dog, eh?
No.
That dog's a menace. l'm taking
him to make sure he's destroyed.
Destroyed! Toto?
Oh, you can't! You mustn't!
Auntie Em! Uncle Henry!
You won't let her, will you?
Of course we won't.
Will we, Em?
Please, Aunt Em!
Toto didn't know he was
doing anything wrong.
l'm the one that ought to be punished.
Send me to bed without supper.
Hand over that dog or l'll bring
a suit that'll take your farm!
The law protects folks
against dogs that bite!
How about if she ties him up?
He's gentle.
-With gentle people, that is.
-That's for the sheriff to decide.
This order allows me to take him.
Unless you want to go against the law.
We can't go against the law.
l'm afraid Toto has to go.
Now you're seeing reason.
Here's what l'm taking him in,
so he can't attack me again.
l won't let you take him!
You go away!
l'll bite you myself!
You wicked old witch! Uncle Henry,
Auntie Em, don't let her take Toto!
l've got an order!
Let me have him!
Put him in the basket, Henry.
-The idea!
-Don't, Uncle Henry.
Oh, Toto!
Almira Gulch, just because
you own half the county...
...doesn't mean you can
run the rest of us!
For 23 years l've been dying
to tell you what l thought of you!
And now--
Well, being a Christian woman,
l can't say it!
Toto, darling!
l got you back!
You came back!
l'm so glad!
They'll be coming back
for you in a minute.
We've got to get away!
We've got to run away!
Well, well, well!
Houseguests, eh?
And who might you be?
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
Let's see.
You're traveling in disguise.
No, that's not right.
You're going on a visit.
No, l'm wrong.
You're running away.
How did you guess?
Professor Marvel never guesses.
He knows!
Now, why are you running away?
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
They don't understand you at home.
They don't appreciate you.
You want to see other lands.
Big cities, big mountains, big oceans.
Why, it's just like you could
read what was inside of me.
Toto, that's not polite!
We haven't been asked yet.
He's perfectly welcome.
As one dog to another, huh?
Here now, where were we...?
Why can't we go with you
and see the crowned heads of Europe?
Do you know any?
Oh, you mean the thing....
l never do anything without
consulting my crystal first.
Let's go inside here. We'll--
Just come along. l'll show you.
That's right. Here.
Sit right down here.
That's it.
This is the same genuine,
magic, authentic crystal...
...used by the priests of lsis and
Osiris in the days of the Pharaohs...
...in which Cleopatra saw the approach
of Julius Caesar and Marc Anthony.
And so on, and so on.
Now, you'd better close your eyes,
my child, for a moment...
...in order to be better in tune
with the lnfinite.
We can't do these things without
reaching out into the lnfinite.
Yes, that's all right.
Now you can open them.
We'll gaze into the crystal.
What's this l see?
A house with a picket fence...
...and a barn with a weathervane...
...of a running horse.
That's our farm!
There's a woman.
She's wearing a polka-dot dress.
Her face is careworn.
That's Aunt Em.
Yes, her name is Emily.
That's right. What's she doing?
Well, l can't quite see.
Why, she's crying.
Someone has hurt her.
Someone has just about
broken her heart.
Me?
Well, it's someone she loves very much.
Someone she's been very kind to.
Someone she's taken care of in sickness.
l had the measles once, and she stayed
right by me every minute.
What's she doing now?
Yes, she's--
What's this?
Why, she's putting her hand
on her heart!
She's dropping down on the bed!
Well, that's all.
The crystal's gone dark.
You don't suppose she could
really be sick, do you?
-l've got to go home right away!
-l thought you were going with me.
No, l have to get to her right away!
Come on, Toto! Come on!
Goodbye, Professor Marvel.
And thanks a lot!
Better get under cover, Sylvester.
A storm's blowing up.
A whopper, to speak in the
vernacular of the peasantry.
Poor little kid.
l hope she gets home all right.
Get them horses loose!
Where's Hickory? Hickory!
Doggone it!
lt's a twister! lt's a twister!
Dorothy!
Everybody in the storm cellar!
Henry, l can't find Dorothy!
She's out in the storm!
We can't look for her now.
Come on, get in the cellar!
Hurry up!
Auntie Em!
Uncle Henry!
We must be up inside the cyclone!
Miss Gulch!
Toto...
...l have a feeling we're not
in Kansas anymore.
We must be over the rainbow!
Now l know we're not in Kansas.
Are you a good witch or a bad witch?
Who, me?
l'm not a witch at all.
l'm Dorothy Gale, from Kansas.
ls that the witch?
Who, Toto? Toto's my dog.
l'm a little muddled. The Munchkins
called me because a new witch...
...just dropped a house on the
Wicked Witch of the East.
And there's the house,
and here you are...
...and that's all that's left
of the Wicked Witch of the East.
What the Munchkins want to know is,
are you a good witch or a bad witch?
But l've already told you,
l'm not a witch at all.
Witches are old and ugly.
What was that?
The Munchkins. They're laughing
because l am a witch.
l'm Glinda, the Witch of the North.
You are?
l beg your pardon!
But l've never heard
of a beautiful witch.
Only bad witches are ugly.
The Munchkins are happy...
...because you freed them from the
Wicked Witch of the East.
But if you please,
what are Munchkins?
The little people who live here.
lt's Munchkinland...
...and you are their national heroine.
lt's all right.
You may all come out and thank her.
Come out, come out
Wherever you are
And meet the young lady
Who fell from a star
She fell from the sky
She fell very far
And Kansas, she says
Is the name of the star
Kansas, she says
She brings you good news
Or haven't you heard?
When she fell out of Kansas
A miracle occurred
It really was no miracle
What happened was just this
The wind began to switch
The house to pitch
And suddenly the hinges
Started to unhitch
Just then the Witch
To satisfy an itch
Went flying on her broomstick
Thumbing for a hitch
And oh, what happened then was rich
The house began to pitch
The kitchen took a slitch
It landed on the Wicked Witch
In the middle of a ditch
Which was not a healthy situation
For the Wicked Witch
The house began to pitch
The kitchen took a slitch
It landed on the Wicked Witch
In the middle of a ditch
Which was not a healthy situation
For the Wicked Witch
Who began to twitch
And was reduced to just a stitch
Of what was once the Wicked Witch
We thank you very sweetly
For doing it so neatly
You've killed her so completely
That we thank you very sweetly
Let the joyous news be spread!
The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead!
Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead
Which old witch? The Wicked Witch
Ding-Dong! The Wicked Witch is dead
Wake up, you sleepyhead
Rub your eyes, get out of bed
Wake up, the Wicked Witch is dead
She's gone where the goblins go
Below, below, below
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing
And ring the bells out
Ding-Dong! The merry-o
Sing it high, sing it low
Let them know
The Wicked Witch is dead
As mayor of the Munchkin City
In the county of the Land of Oz
I welcome you most regally
But we've got to verify it legally
-To see
-To see?
-If she
-If she?
Is morally, ethically
-Spiritually, physically
-Positively, absolutely
Undeniably and reliably dead
As coroner I must aver
I thoroughly examined her
And she's not only merely dead
She's really most sincerely dead
Then this is a Day of lndependence...
...for all the Munchkins
and their descendants.
if any!
Yes, let the joyous news be spread.
The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead!
Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead
Which old witch? The Wicked Witch
Ding-Dong! The Wicked Witch is dead
Wake up, you sleepyhead
Rub your eyes, get out of bed
Wake up
The Wicked Witch is dead
She's gone where the goblins go
Below, below, below
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing
And ring the bells out
Ding-Dong! The merry-o
Sing it high, sing it low
Let them know the Wicked Witch is dead
We represent the Lullaby League
The Lullaby League
And in the name of the Lullaby League
We wish to welcome you
To Munchkinland
We represent the Lollipop Guild
The Lollipop Guild
And in the name of the Lollipop Guild
We wish to welcome you
To Munchkinland
We welcome you to Munchkinland
From now on you'll be history
-You'll be his--
-You'll be history
And we will glorify your name
-You will be a bust
-Be a bust
-In the hall of fame
l thought you said she was dead.
That was her sister,
the Wicked Witch of the East.
This is the Wicked Witch of the West.
She's worse than the other one was.
Who killed my sister?
Who killed the Witch of the East?
Was it you?
lt was an accident.
l didn't mean to kill anybody.
Well, my little pretty,
l can cause accidents too!
-Aren't you forgetting the ruby slippers?
-The slippers. Yes!
The slippers!
They're gone!
The ruby slippers!
What have you done with them?
Give them back to me or l'll--
lt's too late! There they are,
and there they'll stay!
Give me back my slippers!
Only l know how to use them.
They're of no use to you. Give them
back to me. Give them back!
Keep inside of them.
Their magic must be powerful
or she wouldn't want them so badly.
Stay out of this, Glinda,
or l'll fix you as well!
Oh, rubbish!
You have no power here.
Begone, before somebody
drops a house on you too.
Very well. l'll bide my time.
And as for you, it's true l can't
attend to you here and now as l'd like.
But just try to stay out of my way!
Just try!
l'll get you, my pretty...
...and your little dog too!
lt's all right. You can get up.
She's gone!
lt's all right.
You can all get up.
What a smell of sulfur!
l'm afraid you've made an enemy
of the Wicked Witch.
The sooner you get out of Oz altogether,
the safer you'll sleep, my dear.
Oh, l'd give anything
to get out of Oz altogether.
But which is the way back to Kansas?
l can't go the way l came.
No, that's true.
The only person who might know...
...would be the great and wonderful
Wizard of Oz himself.
The Wizard of Oz?
ls he good or is he wicked?
Oh, very good, but very mysterious.
He lives in the Emerald City,
a long journey from here.
Did you bring your broomstick with you?
No, l'm afraid l didn't.
Well, then, you'll have to walk.
The Munchkins will see you
to the border of Munchkinland.
And remember, never let those ruby
slippers off your feet for a moment...
...or you will be at the mercy
of the Wicked Witch of the West.
But how do l start for Emerald City?
lt's always best
to start at the beginning.
And all you do is
follow the Yellow Brick Road.
-But what happens if l--
-Just follow the Yellow Brick Road.
-Goodbye!
My!
People come and go so quickly here!
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
Follow, follow, follow, follow
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
Follow the Yellow Brick
You're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
You'll find he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
Because, because, because
Because, because
Because of the wonderful things he does
You're Off to See the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
Follow the Yellow...?
Now which way do we go?
Pardon me!
That way is a very nice way.
Who said that?
Don't be silly, Toto.
Scarecrows don't talk.
lt's pleasant down that way too.
That's funny.
Wasn't he pointing the other way?
Of course, people do go both ways.
Why, you did say something, didn't you?
Are you doing that on purpose,
or can't you make up your mind?
That's the trouble.
l can't make up my mind.
l haven't got a brain.
Only straw.
How can you talk if you
haven't got a brain?
l don't know.
But some people without brains
do a lot of talking, don't they?
Yes, l guess you're right.
Well, we haven't really
met properly, have we?
Why, no.
How do you do?
-Very well, thank you.
-l'm not feeling at all well.
lt's very tedious being stuck up here
all day long with a pole up your back.
Oh, dear. That must be terribly
uncomfortable. Can't you get down?
Down? No, you see, l'm--
Well, l'm--
Well, here. Let me help you.
That's very kind of you.
Very kind.
Oh, dear. l don't see....
Of course, l'm not bright
about doing things...
...but if you'll just bend
the nail down, maybe l'll slip off and--
Oh, yes!
There goes some of me again!
Does it hurt you?
l just keep picking it up
and putting it back in again.
My! lt's good to be free!
Did l scare you?
l just thought you hurt yourself.
l didn't scare you?
No, of course not.
l didn't think so.
Boo! Scat! Boo!
You see?
l can't even scare a crow.
They come from miles around just to eat
in my field and laugh in my face.
Oh, l'm a failure, because
l haven't got a brain!
What would you do
with a brain if you had one?
Do? Why, if l had a brain, l could--
I could while away the hours
Conferring with the flowers
Consulting with the rain
And my head I'd be scratchin'
While my thoughts were busy hatchin'
If I Only Had a Brain
I'd unravel every riddle
For any individ'le
In trouble or in pain
With the thoughts you'd be thinkin'
You could be another Lincoln
If you only had a brain
Oh, I could tell you why
The ocean's near the shore
I could think of things
I never thunk before
And then I'd sit
And think some more
I would not be just a nothin'
My head all full of stuffin'
My heart all full of pain
I would dance and be merry
Life would be a ding-a-derry
If I Only Had a Brain
Wonderful!
if our scarecrow back in Kansas
could do that...
-...the crows would be scared to pieces!
-They would?
-Where's Kansas?
-That's where l live.
l want to get back there so badly,
l'm going to Emerald City...
...to get the Wizard of Oz to help me.
You're going to see a wizard?
Do you think if l went,
this wizard would give me brains?
l couldn't say.
But even if he didn't, you'd be
no worse off than you are now.
-Yes, that's true.
-But maybe you better not.
l've got a witch mad at me,
and you might get into trouble.
Witch?
l'm not afraid of a witch!
l'm not afraid of anything!
Except a lighted match.
l don't blame you.
But l'd face a whole box of them
for the chance of getting some brains.
l won't be any trouble,
because l don't eat a thing.
And l won't try to manage things,
because l can't think.
Won't you take me with you?
Of course l will!
Hooray! We're off to see a wizard!
-You're not starting out very well.
-l'll try! Really, l will!
-To Oz?
-To Oz!
We're Off to See the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
Because, because, because
Because, because
Because of the wonderful things he does
We're Off to See the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
Apples!
Oh, look!
What do you think you're doing?
We've been walking a long ways
and l was hungry and--
Did you say something?
-She was hungry!
How would like to have someone come
along and pick something off of you?
Oh, dear!
l keep forgetting l'm not in Kansas.
Come along, Dorothy.
You don't want any of those apples.
Are you hinting my apples aren't
what they ought to be?
Oh, no! lt's just that she doesn't
like little green worms!
Oh, you!
l'll show you how to get apples.
Hooray! l guess that did it!
Help yourself.
Why, it's a man!
A man made out of tin!
Yes...!
Look!
Did you say something?
He said "oilcan."
Oil can what?
Oilcan?
Here it is.
Where do you want to be oiled first?
He said his mouth.
The other side.
My goodness! l can talk again!
Oil my arms, please. Oil my elbows.
Here.
Did that hurt?
No, it feels wonderful.
l've held that axe up for ages.
Goodness!
How did you ever get like this?
About a year ago...
...l was chopping that tree...
...when suddenly it began to rain.
And right in the middle of a chop,
l rusted solid.
And l've been that way ever since.
You're perfect now.
My neck. My neck.
Perfect?
Bang on my chest
if you think l'm perfect.
Go ahead, bang on it!
Beautiful!
What an echo!
lt's empty.
The tinsmith forgot to give me a heart.
No heart?
No heart.
All hollow.
When a man's an empty kettle
He should be on his mettle
And yet I'm torn apart
Just because I'm presumin'
That I could be kind of human
If I Only Had a Heart
I'd be tender, I'd be gentle
And awful sentimental
Regarding love and art
I'd be friends with the sparrows
And the boy who shoots the arrows
If I Only Had a Heart
Picture me
A balcony
Above, a voice sings low
Wherefore art thou, Romeo?
I hear a beat
How sweet!
Just to register emotion
Jealousy, devotion
And really feel the part
I could stay young and chipper
And I'd lock it with a zipper
If I Only Had a Heart
-Are you all right?
-l'm a little rusty yet.
Oh, dear!
That was wonderful!
You know...
...we were wondering why
you couldn't come with us...
...to ask the Wizard for a heart.
Suppose the Wizard wouldn't
give me one when we got there.
Oh, but he will!
He must!
We've come such a long way already.
You call that long?
Why, you've just begun!
Helping the little lady along,
are you, my fine gentlemen?
Well, stay away from her...
...or l'll stuff a mattress with you!
And you!
l'll use you for a beehive!
Here, scarecrow! Want to play ball?
Fire!
l'm burning! l'm burning!
l'm not afraid of her.
l'll see you get safely to the Wizard,
whether l get a brain or not!
Stuff a mattress with me!
l'll see you reach the Wizard,
whether l get a heart or not.
Beehive! Bah!
Let her try and make
a beehive out of me!
You're the best friends
anybody ever had.
And it's funny, but l feel as if
l've known you all the time.
-But l couldn't have, could l?
-l don't see how.
You weren't around when l was
stuffed and sewn together.
And l was standing over there
rusting for the longest time.
Still, l wish l could remember.
But l guess it doesn't matter anyway.
We know each other now.
-That's right.
-We do.
-To Oz?
-To Oz!
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
Because, because, because
Because, because
Because of the wonderful things he does
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
l don't like this forest.
lt's dark and creepy!
Of course, l don't know...
...but l think it'll get darker
before it gets lighter.
Do you suppose we'll meet
any wild animals?
We might.
Animals that eat straw?
Some, but mostly lions
and tigers and bears.
-Lions!
-And tigers?
And bears!
Lions and tigers and bears!
Oh, my!
Put 'em up! Put 'em up!
Which one of you first?
l'll fight you both together,
if you want.
l'll fight you with
one paw tied behind my back!
l'll fight you on one foot!
l'll fight you with my eyes closed!
Pulling an ax on me, eh?
Sneaking up on me, eh? Why....
-Go away and let us alone.
-Oh, scared, huh?
Afraid, huh?
How long can you stay fresh
in that can?
Come on, get up and fight,
you shivering junkyard.
Put your hands up,
you lopsided bag of hay!
That's getting personal, Lion.
Yes, get up and teach him a lesson.
What's wrong with you teaching him?
Well, l hardly know him.
l'll get you anyway, peewee!
Shame on you!
What did you do that for?
l didn't bite him.
No, but you tried to.
lt's bad enough picking on a straw man,
but picking on little dogs....
Well, you didn't have to go
and hit me, did you?
ls my nose bleeding?
Well, of course not.
My goodness, what a fuss you're making!
Naturally, when you go around picking
on things weaker than you are....
You're nothing but a big coward!
You're right, l am a coward!
l haven't any courage at all.
l even scare myself!
Look at the circles under my eyes.
l haven't slept in weeks.
Why don't you try counting sheep?
That doesn't do any good.
l'm afraid of them.
Oh, that's too bad.
You think the Wizard
could help him too?
l don't see why not.
Come along with us.
We're on our way to see the Wizard.
To get him a heart.
-And him a brain.
-He could give you some courage.
Wouldn't you feel degraded to be seen
in the company of a cowardly lion?
l would.
No, of course not.
Gee, that's awfully nice of you.
My life has been simply unbearable.
Well, it's all right now.
The Wizard'll fix everything.
lt's been in me so long.
l just gotta tell you how l feel.
Come on!
Yeah, it's sad, believe me, missy
When you're born to be a sissy
Without the vim and verve
But I could show my prowess
Be a lion, not a mouse
If I Only Had the Nerve
I'm afraid there's no denyin'
I'm just a dandy lion
A fate I don't deserve
-I'd be brave as a blizzard
-I'd be gentle as a lizard
I'd be clever as a gizzard
If the Wizard is a wizard
who will serve
Then I'm sure to get a brain
-A heart
-A home
The nerve!
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
Because, because, because
Because, because
Because of the wonderful things he does
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
So you won't take warning, eh?
All the worse for you, then!
l'll take care of you now
instead of later!
When l gain those ruby slippers...
...my power will be the greatest in Oz!
And now, my beauties...
...something with poison in it, l think.
With poison in it.
But attractive to the eye
and soothing to the smell!
Poppies.
Poppies!
Poppies will put them to sleep.
Sleep....
Now they'll sleep.
There's Emerald City!
Oh, we're almost there!
At last! At last!
lt's beautiful, isn't it?
Just like l knew it would be.
He really must be a wonderful wizard
to live in a city like that!
What are we waiting for?
-Nothing! Let's hurry!
-Yes, let's run!
Come on! Come on!
Hurry! Hurry!
Go! Look!
Come on!
Look at the scenery. lt's wonderful!
Emerald City!
What's happening?
What is it?
l can't run anymore.
l'm so sleepy.
Give us your hands.
We'll pull you.
Oh, no, please.
l have to rest for just a minute.
Toto. Where's Toto?
You can't rest now.
We're nearly there.
Don't cry.
You'll rust yourself again!
Coming to think of it,
forty winks wouldn't be bad.
Don't you start it too!
We ought to carry Dorothy!
l don't think l could,
but we could try.
Now look at him!
lt's terrible!
Here, Tin Man, help me.
This is terrible!
l can't budge her an inch!
This is a spell, this is!
lt's the Wicked Witch!
What'll we do?
Help! Help!
lt's no use screaming
at a time like this.
Nobody will hear you!
Help! Help!
Help!
lt's snowing!
No, it isn't!
Yes, it is!
Maybe that'll help!
Oh, but it couldn't help!
lt does help!
Dorothy, you're waking up!
Unusual weather we're having,
ain't it?
Look. He's rusted again!
-Give me the oilcan, quick!
-Here.
-He is rusted.
-Quick!
Curses! Curses!
Somebody always helps that girl!
But shoes or no shoes,
l'm still great enough to conquer her.
And woe to those who try to stop me!
Let's get out of here.
Look! Emerald City is closer
and prettier than ever!
You're out of the woods
You're out of the dark
You're out of the night
Step into the sun
Step into the light
Keep straight ahead for
the most glorious place
On the face of the earth
or the sky
Hold on to your breath
Hold on to your heart
Hold on to your hope
March up to the gate
And bid it open
To the Emerald City,
as fast as lightning!
You're out of the woods
You're out of the dark
You're out of the night
Step into the sun
Step into the light
March up to the gate
And bid it...
...open
Open
Who rang that bell?
-We did!
-Can't you read?
-Read what?
-The notice!
-What notice?
-lt's on the door!
As plain as the nose on my face!
"Bell out of order.
Please knock."
Well! That's more like it!
Now, state your business.
We want to see the Wizard!
The Wizard?
But nobody can see the Great Oz!
Nobody's ever seen the Great Oz!
Even l've never seen him!
Well, then, how do you know
there is one?
Because he's--
You're wasting my time!
Oh, please. Please, sir.
l've got to see the Wizard.
The Good Witch of the North sent me.
Prove it!
She's wearing the ruby slippers
that she gave her.
So she is!
Well, bust my buttons!
Why didn't you say that
in the first place?
That's a horse of a different color!
Come on in!
Cabby! Cabby!
Just what you're looking for!
Take you any place in the city, we does!
-Would you take us to see the Wizard?
-The Wizard? The Wizard?
Yes, of course. But first l'll
take you to a place...
...where you can tidy up.
Oh, thank you so much!
We've been gone such a long time,
and we feel so mess--
What kind of a horse is that?
-l've never seen a horse like that!
-No, and never will again.
There's only one of him, and he's it.
He's the Horse of a Different Color
you've heard tell about.
Ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ho!
And a couple of tra-la-las
That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
Bzz, bzz, bzz!
Chirp, chirp, chirp!
And a couple of la-di-das
That's how the crickets crick all day
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
We get up at twelve
And start to work at one
Take an hour for lunch
And then at two we're done
Jolly good fun!
Ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ho!
And a couple of tra-la-las
That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
Ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ho!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
That's how we laugh the day away
With a--
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
Pat, pat here
Pat, pat there
And a couple of brand-new straws
That's how we keep you young and fair
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
Rub, rub here
Rub, rub there
Whether you're tin or bronze
That's how we keep you in repair
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
We can make a dimpled smile
Out of a frown
Can you even dye my eyes
To match my gown?
Jolly old town!
Clip, clip here
Clip, clip there
We give the roughest claws
That certain air of savoir-faire
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
That's how we laugh the day away
With a ha-ha-ha
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
Who's her? Who's her?
lt's the witch!
She's followed us here!
"Surrender, Dorothy."
Dorothy? Who's Dorothy?
-The Wizard will explain it!
-To the Wizard!
Oh, dear!
Whatever shall we do?
We better hurry if we're
gonna see the Wizard!
Here! Here, here!
Everything is all right.
Stop that now, just--
lt's all right!
Everything is all right!
The Great and Powerful Oz has got
matters well in hand.
l hope.
So you can all go home!
There's nothing to worry about!
Get out of here. Now go on!
Go on home.
Go home.
We want to see the Wizard right away.
All four of us.
Orders are, nobody can see the Great Oz!
Not nobody, not nohow!
But, please! lt's very important.
l got a permanent
just for the occasion.
Not nobody, not nohow!
But she's Dorothy!
The witch's Dorothy?
Well, that makes a difference.
Just wait here.
l'll announce you at once.
Did you hear that?
He'll announce us at once.
-l've as good as got my brain.
-l can fairly hear my heart beating.
l'll be home for supper.
ln another hour,
l'll be king of the forest.
Long live the king!
If I Were King of the Forest
Not queen
Not duke
Not prince
My regal robes of the forest
Would be satin
Not cotton
Not chintz
I'd command each thing
Be it fish or fowl
With a woof!
And a woof!
And a royal growl
As I'd click my heel
All the trees would kneel
And the mountains bow
And the bulls kowtow
And the sparrow would take wing
If I
If I were king
Each rabbit would show respect to me
The chipmunks genuflect to me
Though my tail would lash
I would show compash
For every underling
If I
If I were king
Just king
Monarch of all I survey
Monarch
Of all I survey
if you were king,
you wouldn't be afraid of anything?
Not nobody, not nohow!
-Not even a rhinoceros?
-lmposserous!
-How about a hippopotamus?
-l'd trash him from top to "bottom-us."
-Supposing you met an elephant?
-l'd wrap him up in "cello-phant" !
-What if it were a brontosaurus?
-l'd show him who's king of the forest!
-How?
Courage!
What makes a king out of a slave?
What makes the flag on the mast to wave?
Courage!
What makes the elephant
charge his tusk...
...in the misty mist
or the dusky dusk?
What makes the muskrat guard his musk?
Courage!
What makes the sphinx
the Seventh Wonder? Courage!
What makes the dawn come up
like thunder?
Courage!
What makes the Hottentot so hot?
What puts the "ape" in apricot?
What have they got that l ain't got?
-Courage!
-You can say that again.
The Wizard says go away!
Go away?
Looks like we came a long way
for nothing.
And l was so happy.
l thought l was on my way home.
Don't cry.
We're gonna get you to the Wizard.
We certainly are.
Auntie Em was so good to me...
...and l never appreciated it.
Running away and hurting her feelings.
Professor Marvel said she was sick.
She may be dying...
...and it's all my fault.
l'll never forgive myself.
Never, never, never.
Please don't cry anymore.
l'll get you into the Wizard somehow.
Come on.
l had an Aunt Em myself once.
Wait a minute, fellas.
l was just thinking, l don't want
to see the Wizard this much.
l better wait for you outside.
-What's the matter?
-He's just scared again.
Don't you know the Wizard will
give you courage?
l'd be too scared to ask him for it.
Well, then, we'll ask him for you.
l'd sooner wait outside.
Why? Why?
Because l'm still scared!
-What happened?
-Somebody pulled my tail.
You did it yourself.
Here.
Come on.
Come forward!
Tell me when it's over!
Look at that. Look at that!
l wanna go home!
l am Oz...
...the Great and Powerful!
Who are you?
if you please...
...l am Dorothy...
...the small and meek.
We've come to ask you--
Silence!
Oh! Jiminy crickets!
The Great and Powerful Oz...
...knows why you have come.
Step forward...
...Tin Man!
You dare to come to me
for a heart, do you?
You clinking, clanking, clattering...
...collection of caliginous junk!
Yes, sir.
Yes, Your Honor.
You see...
...a while back, we were walking down
the Yellow Brick Road--
Quiet!
And you, Scarecrow...
...have the effrontery
to ask for a brain...
...you billowing bale of bovine fodder!
Yes, Your Honor.
l mean, Your Excellency.
l mean, Your Wizardry!
Enough!
And you, Lion!
Well?
You ought to be ashamed of yourself...
...frightening him like that
when he came to you for help!
Silence...
...whippersnapper!
The beneficent Oz has every intention
of granting your requests.
What's that? What'd he say?
What'd he say?
But first, you must prove
yourselves worthy...
...by performing a very small task.
Bring me the broomstick
of the Witch of the West.
But if we do that,
we'll have to kill her to get it.
Bring me her broomstick...
...and l'll grant your requests.
Now go!
But what if she kills us first?
l said go!
"l'd turn back if l were you."
l believe there's spooks around here.
That's ridiculous!
Spooks! That's silly.
Don't you believe in spooks?
No. Why, only--
Are you all right?
l do believe in spooks.
l do, l do, l do, l do.
l do, l do, l do, l do, l do!
You'll believe in more than that
before l'm finished with you.
Take your army and bring me
that girl and her dog.
Do what you like with the others,
but l want her alive.
They'll give you no trouble.
l promise you that.
l've sent a little insect on ahead
to take the fight out of them.
Take special care of those slippers.
l want those most of all.
Now, fly! Fly!
Bring me that girl and her slippers!
Help! Help!
Go away now!
Toto! Toto! Help!
Help! Help! Help!
What happened to you?
They tore my legs off
and threw them over there!
Then they took my chest
and threw it over there!
That's you all over.
They sure knocked
the stuffings out of you.
Don't stand there. Put me together.
We've got to find Dorothy!
Now, let's see....
What a nice little dog.
And you, my dear.
What an unexpected pleasure.
lt's so kind of you to visit me
in my loneliness.
What are you gonna do with my dog?
Give him back!
All in good time, my little pretty.
All in good time.
Please give me back my dog.
Certainly, certainly...
...when you give me those slippers.
But the Good Witch told me not to.
Very well.
Throw that basket in the river.
No! You can have your old slippers,
but give me back Toto!
That's a good little girl.
l knew you'd see reason!
l'm sorry! l didn't do it.
Can l still have my dog?
No! Fool that l am,
l should have remembered...
...those slippers will
never come off...
...as long as you're alive.
But that's not what's worrying me.
lt's how to do it.
These things must be done delicately...
...or you hurt the spell.
-Run, Toto, run!
-Catch him, you fool!
Run, Toto, run!
He got away! He got away!
Which is more than you will!
Drat, you and your dog!
You've been more trouble to me
than you're worth.
But it'll soon be over now!
Do you see that?
That's how much longer
you've got to be alive.
And it isn't long, my pretty.
lt isn't long!
l can't wait forever
to get those shoes!
l'm frightened.
l'm frightened, Auntie Em!
Where are you?
lt's me. lt's Auntie Em.
We're trying to find you.
Where are you?
l'm here in Oz, Auntie Em.
l'm locked up in the Witch's castle...
...and l'm trying to get home to you,
Auntie Em!
Oh, Auntie Em, don't go away!
l'm frightened!
Come back! Come back!
"Auntie Em, Auntie Em! Come back!"
l'll give you Auntie Em, my pretty!
Look! There's Toto!
Where'd he come from?
Why, don't you see?
He's come to take us to Dorothy.
Come on, fellas!
l hope my strength holds out.
l hope your tail holds out.
What's that?
That's the castle of the Wicked Witch!
-Dorothy's in that awful place?
-l hate to think of her in there.
-We've got to get her out.
-Don't cry now.
We haven't got the oilcan, and you've
been squeaking enough as it is.
Who's them? Who's them?
-l've got a plan how to get in there.
-Fine. He's got a plan.
-And you're gonna lead us.
-Yeah.
-Me?
-Yes, you.
-l gotta get her out of there?
-That's right.
All right, l'll go in there
for Dorothy.
Wicked Witch or no Wicked Witch...
...guards or no guards,
l'll tear them apart.
l may not come out alive,
but l'm going in there.
-There's only one thing l want you to do.
-What's that?
Talk me out of it.
-No, you don't!
-Oh, no.
-Now, wait a minute.
-Up!
Come on, l've got another idea.
Do you think it would be polite,
dropping in like this?
Where do we go now?
There!
Wait! We better make sure.
Dorothy, are you in there?
lt's us!
Yes!
lt's me! She's locked me in!
We gotta get her out! Open the door!
Oh, hurry! Please hurry!
The hourglass is almost empty!
Stand back!
l knew you'd come!
l knew you would!
Hurry, we've got no time to lose!
Going so soon?
l wouldn't hear of it.
Why, my little party's just beginning.
Trapped.
Trapped like mice...rats!
That's right.
Don't hurt them right away.
We'll let them think about it
a little first.
Seize them! Seize them!
Stop them, you fools!
There they go! Now we've got them!
Half you go this way,
half you go that way.
Hurry! Hurry!
Where do we go now?
This way. Come on!
Back! Back!
Well!
Ring-around the rosie,
a pocket full of spears!
Thought you'd be pretty foxy,
didn't you?
The last to go will see
the first three go before her.
And her mangy little dog too!
How about a little fire, Scarecrow?
Help! l'm burning! l'm burning!
lt's burning!
Don't touch that water!
You cursed brat!
Look what you've done!
l'm melting! Melting!
What a world! What a world!
Who would've thought
a good little girl like you...
...could destroy
my beautiful wickedness?
Look out! Look out!
l'm going.
She's dead. You've killed her.
l didn't mean to kill her.
Really, l didn't.
lt's just that he was on fire.
Hail to Dorothy!
The Wicked Witch is dead!
Hail! Hail to Dorothy!
The broom.
-May we have it?
-Please. And take it with you.
Thank you so much!
Now we can go tell the Wizard
the Wicked Witch is dead!
The Wicked Witch is dead!
Can l believe my eyes?
Why have you come back?
Please, sir. We've done
what you told us.
We've brought you the broomstick
of the Wicked Witch.
We melted her.
You liquidated her, eh?
Very resourceful.
Yes, sir.
So we'd like you to keep
your promise to us, if you please.
Not so fast. Not so fast!
l'll have to give the matter
a little thought.
Go away and come back tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
But l want to go home now!
You've had plenty of time already.
Do not arouse the wrath
of the Great and Powerful Oz!
l said come back tomorrow!
if you were really great and powerful,
you'd keep your promises.
Do you presume to criticize
the Great Oz?
You ungrateful creatures!
Think yourselves lucky that l'm
giving you audience tomorrow...
...instead of 20 years from now!
The Great Oz has spoken!
Pay no attention to that man
behind the curtain.
The Great and--
Oz has spoken.
Who are you?
Well, l am the Great and Powerful
Wizard of Oz.
You are?
l don't believe you!
l'm afraid it's true.
There's no other Wizard except me.
You humbug!
Yes, that's exactly so. l'm a humbug.
You're a very bad man!
No, my dear. l'm a very good man.
l'm just a very bad wizard.
What about the heart
you promised Tin Man?
And the courage you promised
Cowardly Lion?
And Scarecrow's brain?
Why, anybody can have a brain.
That's a very mediocre commodity.
Every pusillanimous creature
that crawls on the earth...
...or slinks through slimy seas
has a brain.
Back where l come from,
we have universities...
...seats of great learning,
where men go to become great thinkers.
They think deep thoughts,
and with no more brains than you have.
But they have one thing
you haven't got. A diploma.
Therefore, by virtue
of the authority vested in me...
...by the Universitatus Committeeatum
E Pluribus Unum...
...l hereby confer upon you...
...the honorary degree of Th.D.
Th.D.?
That's Doctor of Thinkology.
The sum of the square roots of
two sides of an isosceles triangle...
...is equal to the square root
of the remaining side.
Oh, joy! Rapture!
l've got a brain!
How can l thank you enough?
Well, you can't.
As for you, my fine friend...
...you're a victim
of disorganized thinking.
You are under the delusion
that because you run away from danger...
...you have no courage.
You're confusing courage with wisdom.
Back where l come from,
we have men who are called "heroes."
Once a year, they take
their fortitude out of mothballs...
...and parade it down the main street.
And they have no more courage
than you have.
But they have one thing
that you haven't got. A medal.
Therefore...
...for meritorious conduct,
extraordinary valor...
...conspicuous bravery
against wicked witches...
...l award you the Triple Cross.
You are now a member
of the Legion of Courage.
Shucks, folks, l'm speechless.
As for you, my galvanized friend,
you want a heart.
You don't know how lucky you are
not to have one.
Hearts will never be practical
until they can be made unbreakable.
But l still want one.
Back where l come from, there are men
who do nothing all day but good deeds.
They are called phil--
Good-deed-doers. And their hearts
are no bigger than yours.
But they have one thing
you haven't got. A testimonial.
Therefore, in consideration
of your kindness...
...l take pleasure at this time
in presenting you...
...with a small token
of our esteem and affection.
And remember, my sentimental friend...
...that a heart is not judged
by how much you love...
...but by how much you are loved
by others.
lt ticks!
Listen! Look, it ticks!
Read what my medal says. "Courage."
Ain't it the truth!
Oh, they're all wonderful.
Hey, what about Dorothy?
Yes, how about Dorothy?
Dorothy next.
l don't think there's anything
in that black bag for me.
You force me into
a cataclysmic decision.
The only way to get Dorothy to Kansas
is for me to take her myself.
Oh, will you? Could you?
But are you clever enough to manage it?
Child, you cut me to the quick!
l'm an old Kansas man myself...
...born and bred
in the western wilderness...
...premier balloonist par excellence to
the Miracle Wonderland Carnival Company.
Until one day, while performing
feats of stratospheric skill...
...never before attempted
by civilized man...
...an unfortunate phenomena occurred.
The balloon failed
to return to the fair.
lt did?
Weren't you frightened?
You are talking to a man who has
laughed in the face of death...
...sneered at doom and chuckled
at catastrophe. l was petrified.
Suddenly the wind changed...
...and the balloon floated down
into this noble city...
...where l was instantly acclaimed Oz,
the first wizard deluxe!
Times being what they were,
l accepted the job...
...retaining my balloon
against the advent of a quick getaway.
And in that balloon, dear Dorothy...
...you and l will return to
the land of E Pluribus Unum.
My friends. l mean, my friends!
This is positively the finest
exhibition ever to be shown...
...be that as it may.
l, your Wizard per ardua ad alta...
...am about to embark
upon a hazardous...
...and technically
unexplainable journey...
...into the outer stratosphere!
To confer, converse...
...and otherwise hobnob
with my brother wizards.
And l hereby decree
that until what time...
...if any, that l return...
...the Scarecrow, by virtue
of his highly superior brains...
...shall rule in my stead...
...assisted by the Tin Man,
by virtue of his magnificent heart...
...and the Lion,
by virtue of his courage.
Obey them as you would me.
Thank you.
Come back!
Don't go without me.
l'll be right back.
Stop that dog!
This is a highly irregular procedure.
This is absolutely unprecedented!
Ruined my exit!
Come back! Come back!
Don't go without me!
Please come back!
l can't come back!
l don't know how it works!
Goodbye, folks!
Goodbye!
Now l'll never get home.
Stay with us then, Dorothy.
We all love you.
We don't want you to go.
That's very kind of you...
...but this could never be like Kansas.
Auntie Em must have stopped wondering
what happened to me by now.
Oh, Scarecrow, what am l going to do?
Look!
Here's someone who can help you!
Will you help me? Can you help me?
You don't need help any longer.
You've always had the power
to go back to Kansas.
l have?
Why didn't you tell her before?
Because she wouldn't have believed me.
She had to learn it for herself.
What have you learned, Dorothy?
l think that it...
...that it wasn't enough just to want
to see Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
And it's that if l ever go looking
for my heart's desire again...
...l won't look any further
than my own back yard...
...because if it isn't there...
...l never really lost it
to begin with.
ls that right?
That's all it is.
But that's so easy!
l should've thought of it for you.
l should've felt it in my heart.
She had to find it out for herself.
Now those magic slippers will
take you home in two seconds.
-Toto too?
-Toto too.
-Now?
-Whenever you wish.
Oh, dear.
That's too wonderful to be true!
lt's gonna be so hard
to say goodbye.
l love you all too.
Goodbye, Tin Man.
Don't cry.
You'll rust so dreadfully.
Here. Here's your oilcan.
Goodbye.
Now l know l've got a heart...
...because it's breaking.
Goodbye, Lion.
l know it isn't right...
...but l'm gonna miss the way
you used to holler for help...
...before you found your courage.
l would never have found it
if it hadn't been for you.
l think l'll miss you most of all.
Are you ready now?
Say goodbye, Toto.
Yes, l'm ready now.
Then close your eyes...
...and tap your heels
together three times...
...and think to yourself...
..."There's no place like home.
There's no place like home."
There's no place like home.
Wake up, honey.
Dorothy, dear. lt's Aunt Em, darling.
Oh, Auntie Em, it's you!
-Yes, darling.
-Hello there! Anybody home?
l dropped by because l heard
the little girl got caught in the big--
She seems all right now.
She got quite a bump.
We kind of thought
she was gonna leave us.
But l did leave you.
That's just the trouble.
And l tried to get back for days!
There, there, lie quiet now.
You just had a bad dream.
Remember me...
...your old pal, Hunk?
And me...
...Hickory?
You couldn't forget my face,
could you?
But it wasn't a dream.
lt was a place.
And you and you and you...
...and you were there.
But you couldn't have been, could you?
We dream lots of silly things
when we--
No, Aunt Em, this was
a real, truly live place.
And l remember that some of it
wasn't very nice...
...but most of it was beautiful.
But just the same, all l kept saying
to everybody was, "l want to go home!"
And they sent me home.
Doesn't anybody believe me?
Of course we believe you, Dorothy.
But anyway, Toto, we're home!
Home!
And this is my room...
...and you're all here.
And l'm not going to leave here
ever, ever again...
...because l love you all.
And oh, Auntie Em...
...there's no place like home!